# DR. MARC GALLAND

Plant Biologist turned bioinformatician and data analyst. Lead the Amsterdam Science Park Study Group. Build ad hoc analytical pipelines for figure creation and data processing. Offer support and training in data analysis, statistics and research data management. Extended CV available at https://www.mgalland.info/CV/



#### CONTACT

m.galland@uva.nl

+316.28.19.36.44

F. D. Kahlenbergstraat 111, Amsterdam

www.mgalland.info

@mgalland

in marc-galland

0000-0003-2161-8689

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Programming**

**Python** Shell

Software & Tools Visualisation (R ggplot2, Python plotnine) Data analysis (R tidyverse, Python Pandas & scikit-learn) **Docker, Singularity** Version control: git, GitHub Research Data Management

Zenodo **Utrecht University YODA iRODS** Languages

French **English Spanish Dutch** 

#### **DATACAMP CERTIFICATES**

Python basics and advanced Python Data Science Toolbox Part 1 and 2 Supervised learning with scikit-learn

### CARPENTRIES FOUNDATION

Official instructor since 2018 6 SWC/DC Carpentry workshops

## **WORK HISTORY**

## 05/2017 - Present

**Q** University of Amsterdam Bioinformatics, support in data analysis, Pipeline development, teaching & training

**6** 05/2014 - 04/2017

**♀** University of Amsterdam Tomato genomics, insect resistance

**1** 05/2010 - 04/2014

**♀** INRAE, Versailles, France Seed germination, omics data analysis Support data scientist

Post-doctoral researcher

Post-doctoral researcher

### **EDUCATION**

**10/2006 - 12/2009** 

University of Monpellier (France)

PhD in Plant Molecular Biology

# **ACHIEVEMENTS, HONOURS AND AWARDS**

NWO Team Science Award 2020

Marie Curie Sklodowsa Individual Fellowship, 2015-2017

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- ☐ Advanced Forensics (5274ADFB6Y) Introduction to R and multivariate data
- ☐ Keystone Project III: Big Data (5042KPIB6Y) R tidyverse and RNA-seq
- ☐ Tools in Molecular Data Analysis (5224TIMD3Y) R tidyverse and RNA-seq, statistics

### **GENERAL SKILLS**

Problem-solving Collaborative Persistent Strategic Networking with peers Leadership Software engineering **Bioinformatics Statistics** Teaching Training

# **WEEKLY PLANNING**

